# Thiago Rodrigues Oliveira

36 Gardiner Street Upper - Dublin 1, Dublin/Ireland 00 353 89 220 4926 - drg.thiago@outlook.com www.linkedin.com/in/thiagodrigues www.drigues.com

### **Profile**

I am a BSc graduate in Information Technology (CCT Dublin) and an experienced UX/UI Designer and Web Developer seeks face new challenges, to share and improve skills. I am based Dublin since April 2014, and currently working as an UX/UI Designer at Progress Systems.

I have worked for multinational companies, financial sector, start-up enterprises and advertising agencies across different countries. My experience includes end-to-end web and mobile applications with rich user interface/experience through an user research, project conception, prototyping, testing and shipping, all based on design thinking and lean startup methodologies.

8+ years' experience with Adobe Creative Cloud Studio, Web Templates, User Interface, Graphic and Visual Design, Usability, Design Pattern, HTML5, CSS3 (BEM, OOCss, Sass, Bootstrap), Crossbrowser and Responsive Design.

4+ years' experience with Interaction Design, User-Centred Design and Lean Startup Methodologies, Design Thinking, Branding, Advertising and Digital Campaigns, Wireframing, Prototyping, MVP and Business Model.

Knowledge of Python, Ruby on Rails, PHP (Wordpress), JavaScript (JQuery, ReactJs, VueJs) MySql, MongoDB and Full Stack Web Development (Repository, Version Control, Deploy, Linux CLI and DNS), Usability Testing, User Interviewing and Analysis, OKR and Scrum Methodology.

## **Work Experience**

# UX/UI Designer

Dec 2015 - Present

# Progress Systems (Dublin / Ireland)

- User interface design and development of Progress Financial Websites, implementing the front-end based on HTML5 and CSS3
- Designing mobile applications skins for Progress Mobile Banking
- Design graphic, creating banners, flyers, posters for different marketing campaigns
- Wireframing and prototyping web/mobile screens applications
- Debugging and improving legacy front-end code (HTML5 and CSS3)
- Solving customers design needs
- Collaborating directly with developers to improve performance and reduce development time
- Proposing new dev solutions and dealing with developers to make better user experience API

### **Visual Designer**

## MEC English School (Dublin / Ireland)

Apr 2014 - May 2015

Art Director responsible for the company's sales campaign to both local and Latin-American markets. Collaborated on sales strategies, implementing actions to better support for the sales team. Designing and maintenance of front-end website. Making the visual designs for student communication such as print ads, flyers, posters, college signage, templates for email marketing and social media campaigns.

# Product Owner, Full Stack Designer and Developer

April 2011 - Present

### Freelancer

- Consulting and developing projects and products for companies in Dublin (Ireland), Santiago (Chile) and Fortaleza (Brazil)

- Working as a visual designer and making marketing campaigns
- Prototyping, Designing, Developing and Shipping products using PHP (Wordpress), Ruby on Rails, Python (Django), and HTML5, CSS3 (Sass), JavaScript (jQuery) and Bootstrap
- Designing user experience and interface design for mobile device (iOS and Android), websites and games for TV touchscreen.
- Deploying application using CLI, git repository and cloud services such as Heroku, AWS and Microsoft Azure
- Work based on the fundamental design principles, web standards, responsive design and User-Centred Design and Lean Startup (Lean Build Measure) Methodologies.

# **Projects Developed**

# Granber Instant Vouchers (Co-Founder, Product Owner and UX/UI Designer) Mar 2016 - Oct 2017

Granber Instant Vouchers is a startup project that has the goal to provide discounts on special venues without paying in advance or making a book.

The customer pays at the venue with easy validation.

Easy for the customers. Good for the venue.

### My Tasks:

- Responsible for all product cycle, from conception, development, testing, and shipping.
- Acting as a Product Owner, writing business and work flows based on Canvas Business Model, managing tasks using Kanban Board. Delivering results based on Lean Startup Methodology (Learn Build Measure).
- Branding definition, illustrations, icons design and all visual communication.
- Sketching, wireframing, prototyping and developing web/mobile screens applications.
- Usability testing and user interviewing.

### **Educational**

# Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (Level 7)

Sept 2015 - May 2018

College of Computing Technology (CCT) - Dublin / Ireland

### Modules Concluded:

- Java Programming, OOP Constructs, and OO Design Patterns
- Web Development (Ruby on Rails, PHP, Python, MySql, and MongoDB)
- Network Service Management & Virtualization
- Cloud Computing & Platforms

# Languages

English: Full Professional Proficiency (C2)

Spanish: Professional Working Proficiency (B2)

Portuguese: Native

### **Honors & Awards**

# 2ND Place of Startup Weekend Utrecht (The Netherlands)

Startup: Gameday (2017) Duties: Product Designer

### Winner of Startup Weekend Limerick (Ireland)

Startup: Emojo Watch (2015)

Duties: Visual / User Experience Designer

## **Affiliations & Development Group**

Since 2015 - Startup Digest (Competing 5 times at Startup Weekends)

Since 2015 - Google Developer Group Dublin (GDG)

Since 2016 - ReactJs, DublinJs and UX Dublin

Since 2017 - Deep Learning & Python Ireland